Kiran Warren

12 Millbend Cres, Algester, Brisbane 4115

Phone: 0449 794 414

Email: kwarren@thiess.com.au

Summary

I'm a professional and analytical Mechanical Engineer with 9 years of experience in mining industry plant maintenance. After 9 years working in Thiess' support workshops, I have a very good understanding of the rotable component lifecycle and what is involved at every stage of component rebuild.

Educational Background

2007 - 2012

University of Queensland

B. Engineering, Majoring Mechanical Engineering

- Thesis: Modelling and optimisation of PEM fuel cells.
- Major team projects undertaken include:
 - Team leader in bauxite mining plan project, which included resource estimation, equipment, budget, socio-economic considerations, etc.
 - Alteration of a NDT scheme used for composites for helicopter manufacturing in Australian Aerospace.
 - Complete design and analysis of all landing gear components required for an aircraft with specified parameters/stipulations.
- Dean's Commendation for High Achievement:
 - Semester 1, 2008
 - Semester 2, 2008
- Particular interest in Fluid and Mechatronics courses.

2002 - 2006

Kawana Waters State High School

OP: 3, QCS Grade: A

Software Proficiencies

- Microsoft Office Suite (Word, PowerPoint, Excel/VBA)
- Autodesk Inventor and Vault Packages
- Oracle JDEdwards (Inventory, Procurement, Asset Management, Plant Maintenance)
- MATLAB and MATLAB Programming Language
- Python Programming Language
- Solid Edge V20, ST1 and ST2 Modelling Software
- ANSYS Familiar with Computational Fluid Dynamics modules

Employment History

November 2011 - Present

Mechanical Engineer, Thiess Australian Mining

Thiess Brisbane CRC Feb 2019 – Present

- Scheduling of workshop labour to rebuild components to target stock levels and long term planning requirements.
- Liaise with the term long term planning team to form an achievable, scheduled workload for the CRC Brisbane workshop.
- Liaise with the site teams to organise component supply during unscheduled events, such as breakdowns.
- Organise transport of components to and from site, while maximising transport cost efficiency and meeting delivery date targets.
- Enabling CRC operations through component core receiving, work order creation, job pack creation, work order close-out and component dispatch.
- Management of CRC inventory through periodic stocktaking and transferring stock to-andfrom sites. Additionally, periodic review and replenishment of CRC stock at regional warehouses.

Thiess Brisbane CRC Late 2015 – Feb 2019

- Creation and management of the quality documentation required for component rebuilding.
- Creation and management of standard parts ordering documentation and tools.
- Failure analysis and reporting of prematurely failed components. Development of solutions to prevent similar failures occurring in the future.
- Development of a long term forecasting tool used to aid in the financial forecasts of the workshop and give parts suppliers an opportunity to adjust for our future parts consumption.

Thiess Archerfield Workshop

2014 - Late 2015

- Planning, setup and management of major machine rebuilds.
- Creation of quality documentation for component rebuilds.
- Design and drafting of workshop tooling and other ancillary projects.
- Design and drafting of the Thiess Service Efficiency Structure.

Thiess Mackay Regional Office

2013

- Monitoring and analysis of the Queensland fleet reliability. Data and reports presented to suppliers/OEMs to resolve potential product issues.
- Long term planning for the Queensland fleet. Ensured that major components were reserved by suppliers/OEMs to eliminate disruptions to sites' maintenance schedules.
- Setup and management of machine rebuilds completed by third parties.
- Setup and management of component rebuilds/reconditioning completed by third parties.

Vacation Program based in the Thiess Mackay Regional Office Late 2011 – Early 2012

References

Ben Guerra

Phone: 07 3373 4019

Email: bguerra@thiess.com.au

Positions: Workshop Superintendent Relationship with Referee: Manager

Chris McMillan

Phone: 07 3373 4025

Email: cmcmillan@thiess.com.au Positions: Workshop Supervisor Relationship with Referee: Colleague